KENNETH MAI - SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Honolulu, HI 96816 1-808-225-0085 | iamknf@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Full-Stack software engineer proficient in using Javascript for front-end and back-end programming, React, HTML, CSS, API implementing, Node.JS, Express, PostgreSQL, and frameworks like Bootstrap. Experience in the hospitality industry provides advantage in curating first-class solutions for stakeholders while bringing an adaptable and team-oriented approach.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, iQuery

Backend: Node is, Express, RESTful APIs, PostgreSQL

Tools: Mocha, Chai, Knex, Git, GitHub, Heroku, Node Package Manager, Visual Studio Code

Additional Skills: Microsoft Excel and PowerPoint

EXPERIENCE

Thinkful Online

Software Engineering Program

05/2022 - 09/2022

- Learned industry best practices and software development standards with a focus on Javascript, HTML5, CSS3, React Native, Node.js, PostgreSQL, RESTful API's, algorithms, and data structures.
- Developed and deployed mobile-first applications while learning new languages and frameworks, spending several hours per week collaborating with senior web developers in a mentor-student relationship.
- Produced professional projects from concept to completion including:

Restaurant Reservation Application | Link

- Full stack reservation and table management system.
- Implemented react router and express to build a RESTful API in order to make HTTP requests for all of the reservation data stored on the connected PostgreSQL database.
- Created CRUD functions and knex queries to handle data going to and coming from the database.
- Used Git to track changes and versions while keeping sensitive information from repositories.
- Technology: React, Node.js, Express, Knex and PostgreSQL.

Movie Database Application | Link

- Assembled the back end of a movie website allowing any user to search for their favorite movies.
- Used CRUD methods for reviews, and view theaters and movies that are showing.
- Applied router and controller functions to retrieve a user's specific requests.
- Technology: Node.js, Express, and Knex. Version control with Git.

Study Tool Application | Link

- Created an application that allows users to create, edit, and delete decks and cards within them.
- Created a REST API and middleware functions to allow user(s) to create, read, update and delete their perfect deck of study cards.
- Defined routes and URLs, and used state over multiple components.
- Technology: JavaScript, React, Express, Knex, HTML and CSS. Progress tracked with Git.

Waikiki Beach Marriott Resort & Spa

Honolulu, HI

Front Desk Representative

08/2017 - 03/2022

- Provided first-class service to valued guests while representing Hawaii and the Marriott brand.
- Found elegant solutions that met the brand standard for challenges and obstacles.
- Demonstrated exemplary service receiving praise through guest satisfaction surveys by going above and beyond to provide a unique and personalized experience.

Salvatore Ferragamo

Honolulu, HI

05/2016 - 07/2018

- **Brand Ambassador** Represented a luxury Italian brand upholding high standards and expectations from international clientele.
 - Utilized experience traveling abroad to make international quests feel at home by tailoring each guest interaction uniquely for them.

EDUCATION

Thinkful
Certificate, Software Engineering Program

Remote 09/2022

Yoshida Nihongo Gakuin

Shinjuku, JP **Japanese Language** 12/2009

Kapiolani Community College
Associates Degree, Culinary Arts

Honolulu, HI 05/2009